Hi Guys welcome to this new section.
So you have already gone through all the knowledge as you already know everything you need to do.
But now this is the time and we put everything together and apply our knowledge to execute a project.
So in this case in the section we were talking about those individual process groups which consist of
implementing a project from start to finish.
Everything starts from what is known as initiating process.
A second one.
In this process and the cycle would be planning process group then we will have executing process group
monitoring and controlling process group and finally closing process group for the it's going to be
a very detailed section we will cover everything.
In fact we have already covered everything.
It's just that now we need to look at the sequence we need to look at the live documents.
So it's going to be really exciting really happy for you that we have our game so far.
But now you will see lots of assignments a lot of documentation.
Please please this is my humble request.
Please do them because I will show you the sample.
It's more like fill in the blanks you just have to come up with your own ideas.
You will receive templates you just have to enter information there but when you do that when you think
about a project something which is your own word that really helps in clearing the concept.
So whether you are preparing for PMP Exam or just applying what you learned in your day to day job it's
really going to help you if you complete all these assignments and quizzes.
So let's start with initiating process group.
So as you can understand initiating basically means starting the project.
In this case not a lot of these activities only are applicable for initiating a new project but some
of these exercise some of these activities are also needed when you are starting a new phase of an existing
project.
Primarily the purpose here is to inform all the stakeholders of the school subjectives create relevant
documentation get and Dubreuil have a list of stakeholders you are kicking off a project initiating
process that will provide you with a basic foundation which then is used to build upon it.
So it's very good.
And if you make any mistake here they can really take a toll on your project execution.
So it's very important.
Focus on this process group initially scooping financial resources which are required to start a project
are finalized in this process.
So in fact without this process group you won't be able to start the project.
So it's very important.
And if you are starting with a new project then of course you will do all these activities.
But if you are starting a new phase let's say there was a project which was implemented but then few
items were kept for day two for any for the release and now you are restarting that project with a new
face.
You need to review the existing information like project charter and other project documents to ensure
that that old information is still relevant.
If there is any change in the school as teammates or stakeholders it's very important to revisit all
those areas to make sure that the time has not been impacted anything initiating process group consists
of two key activities one is devil project charter which formally authorizes the existence of a project
and identifies stakeholders.
So we would talk about that.
So the primary activity which is happening here is develop project charter.
I think we have already covered this but project charter is the process of developing a document that
formally authorizes the existence of a project without a project charter project managers cannot work
on a project.
In fact it is in the process of project charter and that project managers are usually identified.
Usually it happens before the project is finished but sometimes even the project charter could be approved
and reviewed and then project managers are assigned.
But whenever a project manager is assigned they can not work on the project work unless they have proved
projects short term.
So basically to initiate a project we need to assign the PM before or after approval of the project
charter documents to usually project managers are identified and assigned during the course of project
charter creation.
But sometimes the project charter document could be finished and signed off and then project managers
are assigned especially.
Let's say we have identified that we need to start this project.
But after three months so there is no point in assigning the project manager right now more of a management
description.
Once you are assigned the them you can.
You have to identify the problem.
Now for practical purposes it's fair to assume that they already have identified the problem but now
they need to work on the problem statement which is a formal way of putting problem a statement out
that it could be a one liner it could be a paragraph but a description about underpinning of the problem
which is causing to initiate this project because remember when we talk about a product we are talking
about money.
A lot of mobilization happened in terms of money in the sources.
So unless the Internet does work hard and there is no point in doing this so we need to provide that
justification for the justification we need to put the problem statement out there.
And along with problem statement we will define the project which would simply mean a high level scoop.
I know the kind of things this project is going to deliver.
And all of this will happen as part of prepare the project charter and as I mentioned earlier it is
the process of developing a document which is called Project chart.
It will have all these sections where it will mention all the details about Project Project charter
is the first important document you can see.
You can have other documents before this like business documents.
They are usually created before and project charter but project charter document is made a project does
not exist.
So it's very important to have project charter document.
Without this document you don't have a project manager.
But even if you have a project manager that manager can not ask for anything.
Project manager does not have authority to do anything.
So the charter document will also include the authority for the project manager.
What kind of a project manager can I ask for.
That has to be specified as part of project charter appropriation.
So sponsors are responsible for creating charter and senior management is top of the document.
But usually a sponsor doesn't create a project charter documents.
It's a big task so they usually work with a senior management group and be cleared.
High level details or gather information about the project project managers or business analyst or some
of the professionals in the team like semi's can create project charterers statement but most probably
project managers will create this document body of project chart.
So I would suggest you do dick print out of the slide.
In fact I'm not as disliked as this was and you can defer to it but don't worry I will also have assignment
for you later in the section where you will have to create a project charter document.
Now if you're scared don't worry I will give you a template so and I will also Valke you how we are
doing everything in that project chart.
The statements are doing that it's not a big deal but yes you have to be careful of certain details.
So a regular project charter will have Project Name its purpose a high level description a high level
milestone a high level team works and a stakeholder List Project chart of the state.
Burns will also have information about project managers name their responsibilities a party and support
state and support.
A statement is basically a statement coming from sponsors that the support project managers and their
allies their activities for this project.
And like always will have inputs and outputs for imports.
We have business document which is the business case providing us with the justification.
Then we have agreements enterprise and Lahman two factors and that is these are coming from the organizations.
These are existing materials which we will use for our project charter and the output will be project
charter document and the assumption log.
So we will have to create assumption at this stage based on our current information because remember
we have very limited information at this stage.
So we have to really focus on our assumptions.
Then we have identified stakeholders which we have already covered in the last section.
All those techniques all those tools which we went through are applied here.
So identify a stakeholder is Prosser's part of initiating process.
So to initiate a project you first need to have the project charters and then identify the stakeholders.
Now for practical purpose one more thing which you may have to do is as project manager or part of you
that is to create business documents.
I mean sometimes sponson may ask you to create business documents also.
So business document preparation usually happen before initiating process your management is asking
you to do that will be again done at the national stage of the project and for its inputs and outputs
that will have project charter business documents project management plan project documents agreement's
enterprise and Lahman to factor organizational process assets and for the inputs we have project charter
business documents project management plan and for project documents you won't have too many documents
at this stage.
But whatever document you have so you will use that and agreement's enterprise in my mental factors
organizational process asserts they are going to be there so we will use these documents to identify
their stakeholders.
These documents will provide us information about who are those users who are going to be impacted by
the change.
And then we will reach out to concerned teams of parties to identify and get these names put out.
Fool have stakeholders registered which will have this information about the stakeholders.
The change request project management plan will be updated and the product documents will be updated.
So initially as the input we will use all these documents to identify the stakeholders and then we will
produce this output and at this stage it is important to know that we can create our R-CA matics which
is responsible accountable concerted informed.
These are the four categories of the stakeholders.
So it's better to create this matics where you can have these four rules and then you can you know identify
all the stakeholders and put them into these categories.
It will help you in better communication so if you know that somebody is the responsible to take action
for a particular event or activity you can reach out to them.
If somebody is simply need to be informed and they don't have any other role in it we don't need to
bother them.
So it's a very good and very popular technique to identify our stakeholders and manage it also as part
of initiating process group you can end up creating communication management plan stakeholder engagement
plan for project documents you can create basic change log issue law requirements documentation but
requirements are hardly available so it will be a very high level information about the proposed change.
That said for now thank you.